[{"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395dc", "question": "In The Simpsons, what was Martin's soap box racer named?", "answer": "The Honor Roller", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2a6", "question": "When was actor Humphrey Bogart born?", "answer": "1899", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a05", "question": "What former athlete plays Matthew McConaughey\u2019s father in the movie \"Failure to Launch\"?", "answer": "Terry Bradshaw", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3e9", "question": "How many calories do the US Postal Service stamps contain?", "answer": "One-tenth of a calorie", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a2c", "question": "What novel by Lucy Maud Montgomery became Canada's longest-running main stage musical?", "answer": "Anne of Green Gables", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aef5", "question": "How was the Scottish outlaw Robert MacGregor better known?", "answer": "Rob Roy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8b3", "question": "Mimas orbits what planet of the solar system?", "answer": "Saturn", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2ce", "question": "What is the only mammal that can't jump?", "answer": "The Elephant", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6013697a1381754895396371", "question": "Which American poet won a Grammy for writing a Johnny Cash song?", "answer": "Shel Silverstein -- Best known for children's literature, he also wrote Johnny Cash's country hit, \"A Boy Named Sue\" in 1969.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "593c49fbb8198b9a2b077959", "question": "In which film did Brad Pitt play the role of Mickey O'Neil?", "answer": "Snatch", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7bd0c877e98cb97778952", "question": "What river runs through Baghdad?", "answer": "Tigris", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe76c3eeec85e375820b2ce", "question": "In which U.S. city was cream cheese invented?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea3ccbff048f679a45ab43", "question": "What does the name \"lagomorph\" refer to?", "answer": "Rabbit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad70", "question": "In March of 1968, Cesar Chavez announced a worldwide boycott of what California food product?", "answer": "Grapes", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c86c", "question": "What disease, caused by the bacteria Y. pestis, is spread by fleas and rats?", "answer": "Bubonic plague", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a69c", "question": "The Canadian city of Windsor is linked to what US city by the Ambassador Bridge?", "answer": "Detroit", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b361", "question": "Which planet was discovered in 1846?", "answer": "Neptune", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff665d952a821ff76ae8af4", "question": "What was the first Times Square New Year Eve\u2019s ball made of?", "answer": "The first Times Square New Year Eve's ball was made of iron and wood.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a297", "question": "What was the name of Phil Collins' first solo album?", "answer": "Face Value", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7354beec85e375820b248", "question": "Who said, \u201cThere are a terrible lot of lies going about the world, and the worst of it is that half of them are true.\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ba6", "question": "What famous baseball poem was written by Ernest Lawrence Thayer?", "answer": "Casey at the Bat", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c881", "question": "Other than the bald eagle, what is the only species of eagle found in the US?", "answer": "The golden eagle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6014c8c5fbde8045e48466e0", "question": "Most flowers have an odd number of what?", "answer": "Petals", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58ab1486baab681b09292174", "question": "The Benz Patent-Motorwagen, widely regarded as the world\u2019s first automobile, was first built in what year?", "answer": "1885", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd2d2ca2596a59cbdfbd393", "question": "What state is also known as the Volunteer State?", "answer": "Tennessee", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d9f", "question": "Who played the role of the US president in the movie \"Mars Attacks!\"?", "answer": "Jack Nicholson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390ed", "question": "In popular literature, what is Princess Aurora's better-known name?", "answer": "Sleeping Beauty", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefbde96ce05a3942286ee4", "question": "Who was the creator of \"Star Trek\"?", "answer": "Gene Roddenberry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b039", "question": "What former US President died one week before the 1973 cease fire in Vietnam?", "answer": "Lyndon Johnson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390b3", "question": "Which book has the statement \"all pigs are equal, but some pigs are more equal than others\"?", "answer": "Animal Farm", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9c6", "question": "In which English county is Charnwood Forest located?", "answer": "Leicestershire", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5909d209bb53d1af65886505", "question": "Who played the role of the Grinch in the 2000 film \"How the Grinch Stole Christmas\"?", "answer": "Jim Carrey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdd3", "question": "What Chinese-born architects designed the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame?", "answer": "I. M. Pei", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad1c", "question": "Where was Ben Franklin born?", "answer": "Boston, Massachusetts", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aed", "question": "What is Charlie's last name in Roald Dahl's \"Charlie and the Chocolate Factory\"?", "answer": "Bucket", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389ee", "question": "What city provides the setting for \"The Phantom of the Opera\"?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b575", "question": "How many pounds does a US gallon of water weigh?", "answer": "8.3", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e3a", "question": "Which of the TV's \"Golden Girls\" plays the title character in \"Stop! Or My Mom Will Shoot\"?", "answer": "Estelle Getty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b67f", "question": "Who was the first American president to appear on the cover of \"People\" magazine?", "answer": "Gerald Ford", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b52b", "question": "What does the phrase Magna Cum Laude mean in English?", "answer": "With Great Honor", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab8f", "question": "What countries share land borders with Cambodia?", "answer": "Thailand, Laos and Vietnam", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b8d7532b42d4a3561a9f0c", "question": "In which country would you find the Gruta Canabrava cave?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8f1a101dd7bf43be5e805", "question": "What is the name of Niagara Falls' smallest waterfall?", "answer": "Bridal Veil Falls", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5f164952f9b80650dbe7f92a", "question": "What is Harry Potter's middle name?", "answer": "James", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391cd", "question": "Who directed the movie \"Alien\"?", "answer": "Ridley Scott", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a94", "question": "What was the title of the 2007 Larry the Cable Guy movie where he played a bumbling Army reservist?", "answer": "Delta Farce", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0a3", "question": "What were the surnames of Bonnie and Clyde?", "answer": "Parker and Barrow", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59f47342cfb6472aeed499d5", "question": "What is a \"Papoose\"?", "answer": "A Native American Child", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b69915ae762b54eb9be9418", "question": "Which team did Babe Ruth join in 1920?", "answer": "The New York Yankees", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a28", "question": "What car model gave its name to an alien in \"The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy\"?", "answer": "Ford Prefect", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb34", "question": "In the late 1990\u2019s, what candy bar used the ad slogan \"Two for me, none for you\"?", "answer": "Twix", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ad7ea57b24f84e0b9f9ffd3", "question": "What is the fear of worms, especially parasitic ones, known as?", "answer": "Scoleciphobia, helminthophobia or vermiphobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdc105b469bb8041d07a06d", "question": "What popular holiday beverage contains sugar, milk and eggs?", "answer": "Eggnog", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339416", "question": "Lulu Roman was an original cast member of what long-running television series?", "answer": "Hee Haw", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398ba", "question": "Eddie Murphy was the voice of which character in the Shrek movies?", "answer": "Donkey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc70", "question": "What year did Cheez Whis debut on the market?", "answer": "1952", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397a6", "question": "What name did Nathaniel Dwayne Hale adopt, to hype his pedigree as Snoop Dogg's cousin?", "answer": "Nate Dogg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe52cff1bf59ab7d2e3810b", "question": "How did IPA beer get its name?", "answer": "IPA beer was originally exported to India", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ee7", "question": "What is the name of Ron Kovic's bestselling autobiography?", "answer": "Born on the Fourth of July", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8fc", "question": "According to Toucan Sam, what should you always follow to find Froot Loops?", "answer": "Your nose", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad37", "question": "Who was the 42nd President of the United States?", "answer": "Bill Clinton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3be", "question": "What year was Theodore Roosevelt born in?", "answer": "1858", "category": "history"}, {"id": "597ddf2077980686f722d183", "question": "What year was the first official Association football game played?", "answer": "1863", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a899bd260d398dc9cf7a6a1", "question": "What is the capital of Madagascar?", "answer": "Antananarivo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be3c", "question": "How many on-field players are there in a standard Australian rules football team?", "answer": "Eighteen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133926a", "question": "What movie follows the ins and outs of Lester Burnham's mid-life crisis?", "answer": "American Beauty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff3c2474f032c0db195b480", "question": "What U.S. President worked as a lifeguard?", "answer": "Ronald Reagan was a lifeguard during high school", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c71b", "question": "What word describes a horse with a golden coat and a white or silver mane and tail?", "answer": "Palomino", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff0af93e662d71a53650fc0", "question": "Joseph Pulitzer founded a school of journalism at which university?", "answer": "Columbia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbab", "question": "What game introduced the characters Raiden, Liu Kang, and Sub-Zero?", "answer": "Mortal Kombat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c1a", "question": "What fictional town is the TV show \"SpongeBob SquarePants\" set in?", "answer": "Bikini Bottom", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff513ceff04d658268c92df", "question": "In which battle did Chinese general Zhang Hongfan destroy the last fleet of the Southern Song Dynasty?", "answer": "The Battle of Yamen occurred on March 19, 1279, near present-day Xinhui County, Guangdong Province.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad7e867b24f84e0b9f9ffc3", "question": "Which group released the album \"O.K. Computer\" in 1997?", "answer": "Radiohead", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59523e1d736d4be723796b4b", "question": "In which Canadian city would you find the largest mall in North America?", "answer": "Edmonton", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a9ec20565ad31a57c80d", "question": "The Nazi organization NSDAP stands for what?", "answer": "National German Workers' Party (Nationalsozialistische Deutsche Arbeiterparteiz)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9ed", "question": "How many vehicles did the original \"Gran Turismo\" video game have?", "answer": "140", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa4195c73aa70ea0b70b11", "question": "What territory's flag features three armored legs?", "answer": "Isle of Man", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cf4", "question": "Where did the Gilmore Girls reside?", "answer": "Stars Hollow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8ea", "question": "In golf terminology, what is referred to as an \"eagle\"?", "answer": "2 under par on a hole", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a1e1e78b5a031299b745740", "question": "What year did Great Britain claim the eastern half of Australia?", "answer": "1770", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a4a98c361d1b4d384d5d691", "question": "What is the name of the ranch the Cartwright family operates in the TV show \"Bonanza\"?", "answer": "Ponderosa Ranch", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1ff", "question": "Which country were the 1988 Winter Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c948", "question": "What does a Geophage do?", "answer": "Eats earthy substances", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a009", "question": "What color are Chip 'n' Dale's noses?", "answer": "Black and red", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59523fde736d4be723796b5c", "question": "What year was Hudson\u2019s Bay Company founded?", "answer": "1670", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0e3", "question": "How old was the Elephant Man when he died?", "answer": "27", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58d076f8870e6f05ba600860", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"The Taming of the Shrew\", who is the shrew's father?", "answer": "Baptista Minola", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6010ca6f0775fa611bce67f8", "question": "The \"Malleus Maleficarum\" was a 15th-century guide to dealing with what?", "answer": "Witches -- Witch hunts spread across 15th century Europe, and hunters were guided by many books, including \"Malleus Maleficarum\".", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb26", "question": "What is the common name for coagulated soy milk curd pressed into blocks?", "answer": "Tofu", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a392", "question": "What was renamed to Ho Chi Minh City in 1975?", "answer": "Saigon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b3236bdbf195a31e15d73be", "question": "\"Oliver's Story\" was the sequel to which best-seller by Erich Segal?", "answer": "Love Story", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b037", "question": "What Major League Baseball park was originally called Weeghman Park?", "answer": "Wrigley Field", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfdc", "question": "What sport did Andre Agassi's dad compete in?", "answer": "Boxing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d75", "question": "Who was the first female comic to be called over to the couch by Johnny Carson?", "answer": "Ellen DeGeneres", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389d7", "question": "What artist's largest work is called \"The Night Watch\"?", "answer": "Rembrandt's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7c1", "question": "In pool, what color is the 5-ball?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c042", "question": "What name was given to textile workers who opposed modernisation during the 19th century?\u00a0", "answer": "Luddites\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3c6", "question": "What continent includes Iran?", "answer": "Asia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58c89d11011619dd6d415482", "question": "While pretending to be an inner city calculus teacher, what was Eric Cartman\u2019s catch phrase in South Park?", "answer": "How do I reach these keeeds?", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff256c931a458464a93c461", "question": "What patented structure does Apple feature in its stores?", "answer": "Glass staircase", "category": "general"}, {"id": "597cdde1e347d002c297e4f5", "question": "Which of Shakespeare's plays involves a pound of flesh?", "answer": "The Merchant of Venice", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c297", "question": "What is the name of the number system using only the symbols 1 and 0?", "answer": "The binary system", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59071b743745b36be73039c1", "question": "What year did the Chew comics series debut?", "answer": "2009", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c57a", "question": "What are the four layers of the rainforest?", "answer": "Emergent, Canopy, Understory, Forest Floor", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59071d5e3745b36be73039d7", "question": "What operation brought over 1,500 German scientists, engineers and technicians following the end of World War II to the US to aid in military research?", "answer": "Operation Paperclip", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133963f", "question": "In which country was Greta Garbo born?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4f6", "question": "What planet has a storm system called the \"Great Red Spot\"?", "answer": "Jupiter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c81", "question": "What famous American author published Ulysses S. Grant's \"Personal Memoirs\"?", "answer": "Mark Twain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5e5f0d67d274615ecf514533", "question": "What U.S. President's family home was known as the \"Sherwood Forest Plantation\"?", "answer": "John Tyler", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6008e036f4f3bc4a292f8630", "question": "Who said, \"No one can make you feel inferior without your consent\"?", "answer": "Eleanor Roosevelt (The wife of President Franklin Roosevelt was a political force in her own right.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe52e0c1bf59ab7d2e3810f", "question": "While presenting the first iPhone, Steve Jobs prank called what company?", "answer": "Starbucks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c922", "question": "John Augustus Larson invented what in 1921?", "answer": "Lie detector (Polygraph)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7c73b877e98cb977789c9", "question": "Which national capital does the Vltava River flow through?", "answer": "Prague", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc68", "question": "What college did Brett Favre attend and play football for?", "answer": "Southern Mississippi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ee", "question": "What organization in the Harry Potter series is named after Dumbledore's patronus?", "answer": "Order of the Phoenix", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ae", "question": "What is the name of Johnny Depp's character in \"Pirates of the Caribbean\" movie franchise?", "answer": "Jack Sparrow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ac0", "question": "The French phrase \"espirit de corps\" translates in English to what?", "answer": "Comaraderie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1ca", "question": "For what crime was Bruno Hauptmann executed in 1936?", "answer": "Kidnapping the Lindbergh baby", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339225", "question": "Who plays the role of Craig the puppeteer's wife in \"Being John Malkovich\"?", "answer": "Cameron Diaz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3b3", "question": "What occurs when the Sun and the Moon are in conjunction as viewed from Earth?", "answer": "A solar eclipse", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffb5b525dad637d903c8819", "question": "In what city will you find Le Bourget Airport?", "answer": "Paris, France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0e5", "question": "Which pasta is shaped like a bicycle?", "answer": "Biciclette", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c77ce4924f0f7a362efd545", "question": "A-ha and Edward Grieg hail from what country ", "answer": "Norway", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa4394c73aa70ea0b70b17", "question": "Flanders is part of which country?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a867", "question": "Montenegro's coastline lies on which sea?", "answer": "Adriatic Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac07", "question": "In which continent would you find the Congo River?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9c8", "question": "Which US state has the least rainfall?", "answer": "Nevada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bc1", "question": "Which of David Bowie's eyes has a permanently dilated pupil?", "answer": "Left", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4c6", "question": "Where is Mount Olympus?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59cdb20f65ff7d326b622a70", "question": "What is the study of rocks and their formation called?", "answer": "Petrology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0d5", "question": "How many children did poet Sylvia Plath have?", "answer": "2", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fede6496ce05a3942286dfb", "question": "Who wrote the music for the Holiday classic film \"White Christmas\"?", "answer": "Irving Berlin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad9e06be748bb36357acded", "question": "Jarvis Island in the South Pacific belongs to what country?", "answer": "The United States", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338999", "question": "The story of Samson appears in which book of the Old Testament?", "answer": "Judges", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adbc", "question": "Which country was split into zones by the 'Yalta Agreement'?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b323562bf195a31e15d73ae", "question": "What are the calm weather periods occuring near the Equator called?", "answer": "Doldrums", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015debafe83fe1f2a824b71", "question": "What weapon was developed in 1942 in a secret laboratory at Harvard University?", "answer": "Napalm", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59008ce9cf842fa4c4ba96a4", "question": "Warsaw is the capital of which European country?", "answer": "Poland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2a1", "question": "What sailor's disease resulted from a deficiency of Vitamin C?", "answer": "Scurvy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389dc", "question": "What style of painting are Cezanne, Degas, Manet and Monet all linked with?", "answer": "Impressionism", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecd97dec223966ae8f88e2", "question": "What other name is \"Star Wars\" villain Emperor Palpatine known by?", "answer": "Darth Sidious", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59cdb2c865ff7d326b622a79", "question": "What decade did film start to slowly replace glass in making photographic negatives?", "answer": "1880s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58dba1cb874c93a3298b212b", "question": "How many distinct campaigns did the Crusades have?", "answer": "Nine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b333", "question": "What was founded in the UK in 1694 because of war with France?", "answer": "Bank of England", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bea", "question": "Who created the TV show \"Wheel of Fortune\"?", "answer": "Merv Griffin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca19", "question": "Toxiphobia is a fear of what?", "answer": "Being poisoned", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e8d8fe83fe1f2a824be0", "question": "Who was the last king of the Plantagenet line of monarchs?", "answer": "Richard III", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb55", "question": "Who was the first African-American player inducted into the Baseball Hall of Fame?", "answer": "Jackie Robinson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa40", "question": "What country's explorers discovered the site of Pensacola, Florida?", "answer": "Spain's", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a82", "question": "What female dog is the secret object of Underdog\u2019s affection?", "answer": "Sweet Polly Purebred", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59636b0e967692ea851899a2", "question": "Which \"Committee of Five\" member was the only one to sign all four of the US state papers?", "answer": "Roger Sherman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c00e", "question": "What is the wife of a duke called?", "answer": "Duchess", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cd8", "question": "Who originally sang the 1973 song that became a big Dixie Chicks hit in 2002?", "answer": "Stevie Nicks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b3a2e662d71a53650fe0", "question": "Johann Sebastian Bach wrote a comic opera about which beverage?", "answer": "Coffee", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe65e611f3c0ead6880d62b", "question": "According to the Bible, which Apostle was a tentmaker?", "answer": "Paul", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133918c", "question": "Which witch is flattened by a house in \"The Wizard of Oz\"?", "answer": "The Wicked Witch of the East", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e763fe83fe1f2a824bd2", "question": "Although never taking her seat, who was the first woman to be elected to the houses of parliament in Europe?", "answer": "Countess Markievicz", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3c6", "question": "Which year did Charles J. Guiteau shoot US President James Garfield?", "answer": "1881", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b35", "question": "What is the name of the winged horse of Greek mythology?", "answer": "Pegasus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b689", "question": "Who was the first major league baseball pitcher to throw a no-hitter while wearing eyeglasses?", "answer": "Billy \"Bullfrog\" Dietrich", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339625", "question": "Who starred as Danny Ocean in the 2001 movie \"Ocean's Eleven\"?", "answer": "George Clooney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe378680ada16518afdc051", "question": "Britain annexed Hong Kong as a result of which war?", "answer": "Opium War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "590499eacf93664eb1048695", "question": "Which 1950s film took place in Chicago and Miami in 1929?", "answer": "Some Like it Hot", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3a8", "question": "What was the name of Alexander the Great's famous horse?", "answer": "Bucephalas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339434", "question": "Who co-wrote and directed the 1974 movie \"Young Frankenstein\"?", "answer": "Mel Brooks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ae92b2574a5ce6b56b8231", "question": "Who wrote the 1950s play \"The Rose Tattoo\"?", "answer": "Tennessee Williams", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beef", "question": "If a dish is served pomontier, what does it contain?", "answer": "Potatoes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe52f451bf59ab7d2e38113", "question": "What direction does the Statue of Liberty face?", "answer": "Southeast", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6000edd49a72b906b34e3cf0", "question": "In which part of the body are the ossicles found?", "answer": "Ear", "category": "science"}, {"id": "594a64d92ebb971c1417fba9", "question": "What year did Grace Kelly appear on an US postage stamp?", "answer": "1993", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "596760912b59efe0e9417e9d", "question": "A baby oyster is called a what?", "answer": "A spat", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7cfbe877e98cb97778a53", "question": "Miami, Florida sits on the bank of what bay?", "answer": "Biscayne Bay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f59", "question": "What famous clipper ship took its name from Scots words for \"short shirt\" in a Robert Burns poem?", "answer": "The Cutty Sark", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133998c", "question": "What actor provides the voice for  Sideshow Bob on the TV show \"The Simpsons\"?", "answer": "Kelsey Grammer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c42b", "question": "Which of Jupiter's moons is the most volcanically active body in the solar system?", "answer": "Io", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e963fe83fe1f2a824be5", "question": "Who is Temujin better known as?", "answer": "Genghis Khan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff5150eff04d658268c92e6", "question": "What is the name of the boarding device used by ancient Roman warships?", "answer": "The corvus was a boarding-bridge with a heavy spike designed to pierce the enemy ship's deck when it was lowered.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ccf77dbb37b32637bdc44b8", "question": "Who made \"The Scream\" painting?", "answer": " Edvard Munch", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6a57220565ad31a57c7cc", "question": "In which ancient culture were turkeys believed to be gods?", "answer": "Maya", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefa8d86ce05a3942286ed8", "question": "Who released the album \"Brothers in Arms\"?", "answer": "Dire Straits", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad51", "question": "What U.S. president signed the bill that began Medicaid benefits?", "answer": "Lyndon B. Johnson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5feddd0a6ce05a3942286d9f", "question": "Which country had banned the sale of the original \"Grand Theft Auto\"?", "answer": "In 1998 Brazil banned it (including a $8,500 fine to anyone caught selling it) due to their belief that the game incites violence.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab6b", "question": "What country is East Pakistan now known as?", "answer": "Bangladesh", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bed2", "question": "What is the flower that stands for \"a heart ignorant of love\"?", "answer": "White rosebud", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff6667552a821ff76ae8af7", "question": "What miracle is Saint Valentine said to have performed shortly before his death?", "answer": "According to legend, Valentine restored the sight of his own jailer's daughter.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a594", "question": "What is the smallest ocean?", "answer": "The Arctic Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefa3d86ce05a3942286eab", "question": "Whose hand is shown drawing the charcoal portrait of Kate Winslet in \"Titanic\"?", "answer": "James Cameron's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf15", "question": "What are the Chiuhauhan, Nubian, and Alaskan?", "answer": "Deserts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339584", "question": "Who directed the 1968 movie \"Night of the Living Dead\"?", "answer": "George A. Romero", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b56b", "question": "What is Lipton the world's biggest-selling brand of?", "answer": "Tea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eaa", "question": "What screen legend made her final appearance in the movie \"High Society\"?", "answer": "Grace Kelly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fedda1c6ce05a3942286d81", "question": "Red described geology as the study of what in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Red remarked that geology is the study of time and pressure.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b59e", "question": "How many tiles are there in a standard Scrabble game?", "answer": "100", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1ed", "question": "What cocktail is considered the official cocktail of New Orleans?", "answer": "Sazerac", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339170", "question": "What popular Australian pop star sang the words \"All Beauty Must Die\"?", "answer": "Kylie Minogue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0e2", "question": "Who was the oldest person to sign the Declaration of Independence?", "answer": "Benjamin Franklin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b48c149076251badbeaa6", "question": "Who was the first sitting member of the U.S. Congress to travel in space?", "answer": "In 1985, Senator Jake Garn went into space aboard Space Shuttle\u00a0Discovery's STS-51-D mission as a payload specialist.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ae85f5b4007905755f79e8b", "question": "What is the highest mountain in Africa?", "answer": "Mount Kilimanjaro", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c90cee852800b05cac20f06", "question": "What is the only MLB team that has never had a pitcher throw a no-hitter as of 2018?", "answer": "San Diego Padres", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399fe", "question": "How many episodes of \"The X-Files\" were made?", "answer": "202", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b8a2e662d71a53651026", "question": "Who wrote \"Rip Van Winkle\"?", "answer": "Washington Irving", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab5c", "question": "What is the capital of Rwanda?", "answer": "Kigali", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f0f", "question": "What author created the character of Dr. Gideon Fell?", "answer": "John Dickson Carr", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339163", "question": "Who created the cartoon TV show \"Futurama\"?", "answer": "Matt Groening", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd665bca5bfecdd737e0862", "question": "How long ago did mammoths go extinct?", "answer": "4000 years ago", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3d7", "question": "Who tore up a picture of the Pope on US television in 1992?", "answer": "Sinead O'Connor", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac0c", "question": "In which US state is the Catalina Island located?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b0e8ab964118b2bb3809c6", "question": "Which artist released an album titled \"St. Valentine\u2019s Day\" in 1948?", "answer": "Bing Crosby", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baee", "question": "NAFTA is a trade agreement between the US and what other two countries?", "answer": "Mexico and Canada", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5909d22abb53d1af65886506", "question": "What year did the first Coca-Cola polar bear ad campaign appear?", "answer": "1922", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394e2", "question": "What image appears on The Saint's business card?", "answer": "A stick figure with a halo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f61", "question": "Eric Arthur Blair was better known by what pen name?", "answer": "George Orwell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b49", "question": "Where did the Pied Piper play?", "answer": "Hamelin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e5f", "question": "Who provided the original voice for Shrek?", "answer": "Mike Myers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a3", "question": "What color is Shrek?", "answer": "Green", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51544ff04d658268c92e9", "question": "What countries were involved in the Wars of the Three Kingdoms?", "answer": "The Wars of the Three Kingdoms, aka British Civil Wars, took place in\u00a0England, Ireland and Scotland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133899e", "question": "In music, how should a section labeled as \"fortississimo\" be played?", "answer": "Loudest", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecc81aec223966ae8f888e", "question": "What is the name of the spider that paralyzes Frodo in the film \"The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King\"?", "answer": "Shelob", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c44", "question": "Mort Goldman from the TV show \"Family Guy\", is based on a character from what comedy duo?", "answer": "The Jerky Boys", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e78afe83fe1f2a824bd4", "question": "In medieval history, what was a \"schiltron\"?", "answer": "A battle formation that consisted of soldiers with long spears placed into circular, tightly packed formations", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc65", "question": "What do collectors call the first complete Hot Wheels line-up of cars?", "answer": "Sweet 16", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbcf", "question": "What candy used the ad slogan \"Get the sensation\"?", "answer": "York Peppermint Pattie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7a8", "question": "Defenestration is the act of being thrown out of what?", "answer": "A window", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a9e96467ccba3ffe45786eb", "question": "By what name was Badminton known as in its early days?", "answer": "Poona", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c01c", "question": "What is James Naismith best known for?", "answer": "Inventing Basketball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a55f", "question": "Which state is located directly to the east of Washington D.C.?", "answer": "Maryland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6014c829fbde8045e48466d1", "question": "The Horsehead Nebula can be found in what constellation?", "answer": "Orion", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b423", "question": "In what year did Konrad Adenauer become the first Chancellor of West Germany?", "answer": "1949", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beb9", "question": "Who founded \"Heiress Records\" in 2004?", "answer": "Paris Hilton", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d2c", "question": "The title for the novel \"A Brave New World\" was derived from which Shakespearean play?", "answer": "The Tempest", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6014c4b5fbde8045e48466a0", "question": "What does the African dung beetle use to navigate at night?", "answer": "The Milky Way -- The only animal known to navigate using the Milky Way, they can move objects that are 50 times their weight.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aff5", "question": "Which president accepted the Statue of Liberty on behalf of the American people?", "answer": "Grover Cleveland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339abc", "question": "What sci\u00adfi series, which debuted in 1965, took place in the year 1997?", "answer": "Lost in Space", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9d6", "question": "Coal is predominantly made up of which element?", "answer": "Carbon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600f7298a9e54d890926f6ec", "question": "In which U.S. city can you stroll down 6 1/2 Avenue?", "answer": "New York City -- Made official in 2012, the street is situated between 6th Avenue and 7th Avenue.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389c9", "question": "What New York landmark stands in size 879 sandals?", "answer": "The Statue of Liberty", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c17d", "question": "What is the opposite of an utopia?", "answer": "Dystopia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdcf", "question": "Which two disciples of Jesus were called the \"Boanerges\"?", "answer": "James and John", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a059", "question": "\"Run\" is a 1994 Hong Kong remake of which shoe string-budget action film by Robert Rodriguez?", "answer": "El Mariachi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c392", "question": "What method of food preservation was invented for the British Navy in 1813?", "answer": "Canning", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a8f", "question": "Orlando Bloom portrayed what character in the 2004 film \"Troy\"?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b358c035db0d66a186cb55a", "question": "The \"Arenga Micrantha\" species of flowering plants is more commonly known as what?", "answer": "The Tibetan sugar palm", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6ca", "question": "A tree which is deciduous does what?", "answer": "Loses its leaves every year", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59049a05cf93664eb1048696", "question": "The Queensland nut is another name for what nut?", "answer": "Macadamia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b1743f2bb2d29f81593b6f7", "question": "How is Barbara Millicent Roberts better known as?", "answer": "Barbie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b80", "question": "Who wrote \"Analogy of the Cave\"?", "answer": "Plato", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5952489b736d4be723796b74", "question": "What singer, who went to #1 in 1980 with \"Lookin\u2019 For Love\", published \"Still Lookin\u2019 For Love\", as his autobiography?", "answer": "Johnny Lee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a3d", "question": "The 2002 film \"Confessions of a Dangerous Mind\" was based on the unauthorized autobiography of what former gameshow host?", "answer": "Chuck Barris", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fc9", "question": "What TV show featured the fictional band \"Drive Shaft\"?", "answer": "Lost", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf24", "question": "What does the KonMari Method focus on?", "answer": "Tidying up", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecc080ec223966ae8f885b", "question": "Which actor made his film debut in \"Back to the Future\" as one of Biff's cronies?", "answer": "Billy Zane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339644", "question": "For what film did Robert De Niro learn to play the saxophone?", "answer": "New York, New York", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c420", "question": "How many moons does Mars have?", "answer": "Two", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b234", "question": "What athlete was born in West Baden, Indiana, in December 1956?", "answer": "Larry Bird", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6012188763c99d48cd169af4", "question": "What flavor is Cointreau?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4b9949076251badbeac5", "question": "The Iditarod Trail Sled Dog Race was inspired in part by what event?", "answer": "A diphtheria outbreak -- In 1925, several teams of mush dogs relayed a serum for diphtheria from Seward to Nome, Alaska.", "category": "history"}]